Tilek Zhyrgalbekov

Frontend Developer | Linux System Administrator



Paishkek, Kyrgyzstan in LinkedIn Github

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Over 2+ years of experience specialized in System Administration working on Fedora Workstation, Debian, Arch Linux and Windows environments. Experience in Configuration, Installation, Backup. Recovery, Troubleshooting, Automation and Maintenance. Experience in Installing, upgrading and configuring, Interactive Installation and Shell.

Frontend Developer, performance-oriented, interested in meeting all web needs, as well as with a good experience with the interface and passion for responsive website design and firmly convinced of the approach focused on mobile devices. Assistance in the development and testing of web applications. Constantly recognized for reliability and multitasking.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SAPAT Educational Institution,

Video Editing Software

September 2019 - December 2019 | Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

Light Code, Teaching Assistant

October 2022 - December 2022 | Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

UNO.kg, Frontend Developer

December 2022 - February 2023 | Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

Royal Construction, Frontend Developer □

February 2023 - March 2023 | Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

DevDreamTeam, Frontend Developer | Freelance

January 2023 - Currently working | Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

I am currently working as a freelancer for the DevDreamTeam. We are developing commercial projects there.

EDUCATION

Hussain Karasaev High School

September 2011 - May 2022 Karakol, Kyrgyzstan

IT-Academy

April 2022 - December 2022 Bishkek, Kyrgyzstan

SKILLS

Linux System Administrator Skills

Technical Analysis, Product development, System upgrades, Hardware knowledge, System monitoring, Database Installation and Setup, Application testing, Performance testing, Configuration, Backup, Recovery, Troubleshooting, Automation and Maintenance.

Package Management: DPKG, RPM, Pacman

Scripting: Bash, zsh, Python

Storage environments: SAN, NAS, LVM, BTRFS,

ext4

Server Management: DNS, DHCP, FTP Backup systems: Netbackup, rsync, timeshift

Deep understanding of networking: Iptables, Firewalld, TCP/IP, UDP, Thunderbird

Troubleshooting: top, free, ping, tcpdump,

ssh, netstat, nmap, sqlmap,

wireshark

Knowledge of Virtualization systems: VMware

Knowledge in system security hardening:

SELinux/ACL and chroot etc

Frontend Developer Skills

HTML, CSS, SASS-SCSS, css/scss modules, JavaScript, TypeScript

Frameworks/libraries: React, NextJS

@redux/toolkit.

Bootstrap, Material UI, Ant Design, Framer

Motion, Tailwind

Version control: Git

Debugging

Search engine optimization Cross-browser web development

LANGUAGES

- English
- Russian
- Kyrgyz
- Turkish